Matthew Ramirez

Full Stack Developer

Contact Info:

ADD GOOGLE PHONE NUM HERE

mattramirez244@gmail.com

https://github.com/M-ram224

linkedin.com/in/matthewram

San Diego, CA (Remote)

Summary:

Full stack developer focused on communication and building with a team to create a unique experience inside and out of the application. Each day brings a new exciting problem to solve, granting the ability to complete any task with enthusiasm and motivation. Fulfilling each duty with accountability and efficiency are the strong focus of a ten year veteran in the food industry transfering into tech.

Technical Skills:

Languages: JavaScript, Ruby, SQL, HTML, CSS Frameworks: React, Ruby on Rails

Databases: PostgreSQL, Active Record TTD/Other: Jest, RSpec, Github, Postman

Projects:

Bomb Hunt Game - HTML, JavaScript, CSS <u>Terminal Text Based Game</u> - Ruby

Pig Latin Translator - JavaScript, React, HTML, CSS Wildlife Tracker - Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, Postman

Experience:

LEARN Academy - Web Developer Bootcamp

San Diego, CA | 2020-present

- Completed organized Full Stack training integrating real life programming with hands-on problem solving.
- Experienced 480+ hours of intensive web development education including actively involved pair/ mob programming.
- Invested proficiency in JavaScript, React, Ruby and Rails, practiced test-driven development using Jest and RSpec, and created a Full Stack Application with a PostgreSQL database.

10yr Food Service Industry including:

Coronado Brewing Company Tasting Room - Lead Bartender

Bay Park, San Diego, CA | 2018-2020

- Coordinated quick thinking and team based knowledge to benefit the team and company as a whole.
- Encouraged knowledge in communication while problem solving quickly and understanding needs of others.
- Administered and executed plans with expertise during Covid lockdowns with General Manager.

Georges at the Cove - Expo, Bar-back

La Jolla, CA | 2016-2019

- Expedited precision thinking and focus in a high stress environment to produce above standard quality in product.
- Motivated leadership and coordination skills to stay directed on the team and companies established goals.
- Promoted and familiarized quickly with job duties to give the ability to assist in any situation.

Education:

Crafton Hills College, Yucaipa, CA. 2014-2016 - Courses taken: Geology, Public Speaking, Math, ENG,

Yucaipa High School, Yucaipa, CA. 2008-2011 - High School Diploma, Video Production.